And welcome back to the week six folder.
6주 차 폴더에 잘 오셨어요
We're now at day two, which is the second and final stage of data curation.
이제 이틀째예요, 데이터 큐레이션의 두 번째이자 마지막 단계죠
We're going to be extending our data set to be much bigger.
데이터 집합을 훨씬 더 크게 확장할 거예요
And we're going to craft it into something that is exceptional, uh, just right.
그걸 가지고 아주 특별하고 완벽한 요리를 만들 거예요
For our training purposes, uh, we start with some imports and setting up our environment and logging
훈련을 위해 수입과 환경 설정 포옹 로깅으로 시작합니다
into hugging face, and we get ourselves ready.
그리고 준비하죠
So last time I talked about a Python module called items that I wrote that allows us to parse our data
지난 시간에는 파이썬 을 이용한 모듈을 다뤘었죠. 제가 작성한 항목으로 데이터 포인트를 좋은 항목으로
points into a nice item.
구문 분석할 수 있었죠.
You remember it well, and hopefully you have spent some time digging through this yourself and confirming
잘 기억하시니 시간을 들여 직접 살펴보면서 작동 원리를 확인하셨길
the way that it works.
바라요
There's another Python module that I've made that is shorter and simpler called loaders, uh, which
제가 만든 파이썬 툴의 다른 모듈은 더 짧고 간단합니다 로더라고 합니다
has a single class item loader and is just a nice way to load in one of the data sets from the hugging
단일 클래스 아이템 로더를 가지고 있고 포옹하는 얼굴 저장소에서 데이터셋을 가져오는 좋은
face repository.
방법이죠
And what it's going to do is it's going to use some fancy, uh, stuff from the concurrent futures package
하는 일은 몇 가지 복잡한 것을 이용하는 것입니다 파이썬 에서의 동시 미래 패키지에서 여러 작업자와
in Python to do this with multiple workers, because otherwise this takes a long time.
함께 작업합니다 그렇지 않으면 시간이 오래 걸리기 때문이죠
Now, you don't need to do look through this in too much detail.
너무 자세히 볼 필요는 없어요
There's a few things that I want to tell you about, and then you should just convince yourself that
몇 가지 말씀드릴 게 있는데 다시 틀에 적힌 대로 잘되고
it's doing what it says on the tin again.
있다고 스스로를 설득해 보세요
Uh, so the main, uh, method that gets called is called load.
주요 메서드는 로드라고 불려요
And you pass in a number of workers and by default it assumes eight workers.
작업자 수를 전달하면 자동으로 8명으로 추정하죠
I'm working on a MacBook Pro here that has eight cores and so it can handle it.
맥북 프로를 작업 중인데 코어가 8개라 감당할 수 있어요
It does really hammer my machine.
제 기계가 정말 망가졌어요
While this is going.
이걸 하는 동안에요
You might want to pass in a smaller number of workers, depending on how much you're willing to give
더 적은 수의 작업자를 통과시키고 싶을 수도 있죠 얼마나 기꺼이 머신의 CPU를 포기할지에
up your machine's CPU if you're not doing other things at the same time.
따라서요 동시에 다른 것을 하지 않을 경우에요
Uh, so then, um, this load in parallel method is the one that uses this process.
이 load in parallel 메서드가 이 프로세스를 사용하는 메서드예요
Pool executor.
수영장 집행인요
If you're familiar, if you have used this before, this basically spawns a number of other.
익숙하시다면, 전에 사용해 보셨다면 기본적으로 다른 여러 개를 생성하죠
Um, I've just seen a mistake there that that should obviously say workers so that, uh, it does actually
여기서 실수를 발견했어요 노동자라고 써야 하는데 실제로는 노동자 8명을 쓰고
use the eight workers.
있네요
Otherwise it will always be using six.
안 그러면 항상 6개를 사용하죠
Uh, so this, um, this will spawn up, uh, the number of workers that are specified, uh, and it
이건 지정된 작업자 수를 생성할 겁니다 그런 다음 각각의 데이터
will then load in each of our data points, but it will do so in chunks.
포인트를 로드하는데 단위로 하죠
And you can see that that really what I've done is I've just created a generator familiar with generators
제가 한 일은 발생기를 만든 겁니다 발생기에 익숙한 거죠 결과를
now because of us using them earlier with when we're streaming back results.
스트리밍백할 때 앞서 사용했으니까요
Um, but we're using a generator to, to chop up our data set into chunks of.
하지만 우리는 발전기를 사용해서 데이터를 토막 내고 있어요
As it happens, I set a chunk size here of 1000.
마침 여기 1000으로 덩어리를 설정했네요
So a thousand data points at a time.
한 번에 1,000개의 데이터 포인트가 있는 거죠
So it's chunked up into sets of 1000 data points at a time.
한 번에 1,000개의 데이터 포인트로 나누어져 있죠
And each chunk is then passed in and ultimately made to create a new data point using the same item
각각의 덩어리는 전달되고 궁극적으로 새 데이터 포인트를 생성합니다 지난 시간에 작업했던 동일한 아이템
class that we worked on last time.
클래스를 이용해서요
So no real magic here.
진짜 마법은 아니군요
This is just some fancy packaging to load in items in an efficient way.
효율적으로 물건을 담기 위한 화려한 포장일 뿐이에요
1000 at a time and spread out across eight different workers.
한 번에 천 개씩 8명의 노동자에게 나눠 주죠
But I will say it's worth reviewing this code because this is something that's the kind of thing, again,
하지만 이 코드를 검토할 가치가 있다고 말씀드리고 싶네요 왜냐하면 이건 이런 종류의 것이니까요
that one tends to do a lot with these kinds of projects.
이런 종류의 프로젝트에서 많은 일을 하죠
You need to make good use of your box because it's going to be hefty, and the the kinds of tasks involved
상자는 무거우니 잘 활용해야 합니다 그리고 여러 인부로 나누어
often are very suitable for being divided into multiple workers.
작업하기 좋은 경우가 많죠
And this code should be quite reusable.
이 코드는 재사용이 가능해야 해요
I've hopefully written it in a way that's easy to read and and and reuse so much encourage you to do
읽기 쉽게 썼으면 좋겠고 재사용도 많이 했으니 여러분도 그렇게 하세요
Um, and uh, there is one other little trick that I want to point out, not a another trick.
트릭이 하나 더 있는데 지적하고 싶어요 트릭은 아니고요
Sorry.
미안해요
One other, um, uh, decision that has been made that is going to affect our results.
또 다른 결정이 내려졌는데 그게 결과에 영향을 미칠 거예요
Uh, I've decided that we will select only products which cost anywhere between $0.50 and $999 and and
0달러 미만 제품만 고르기로 결정했어요 50달러, 999달러 그리고 0달러요
So we're going to limit it to things that price in that range.
49살요
And there's various reasons I did that.
여러 가지 이유가 있어요
Um, one is that if you take things that, uh, that go, uh, much more than that number than then
첫째, 그 수치보다 훨씬 더 큰 수치가 나오면 그 결과가 왜곡될
the results are distorted.
수 있어요
There's a very small number of things with a huge price and that can completely mess up things like
적은 것에는 큰돈이 들 수 있습니다 그래서 테스트 성능 같은 걸 완전히 망칠
our test performance.
수 있죠
If we happen to pick something that costs an enormous amount, then our errors can be wild if we're
만약 엄청나게 비싼 걸 골랐다면 비트만 잘못돼도 엄청난 오류가 날 수
off by a bit.
있어요
And because we do want to be using absolute error, just the difference between the recommended price
절대 오류를 사용해야 하니까요 권장 가격과 실제 가격의
and the actual price.
차이죠
It's nice if we can keep our prices within a reasonable range so that we have a pretty decent sense
가격을 합리적인 범위 내에 유지하면 모델 성능을 알 수
of how the model's performing, and we don't have any wild things out there.
있고 이상한 게 나오지 않아요
So essentially, I'm saying for the scope of this project, for what we're doing, we are going to be
본질적으로 이 프로젝트의 스코프에서 우리가 하는 걸 위해서는 1,000달러
talking about things that cost under $1,000.
이하의 것에 대해 얘기할 거예요
That's going to be our scope, and it allows us to focus in our data set.
그게 우리 스코프가 될 겁니다 데이터 집합에 집중할 수 있게 해주죠
You could also experiment with doing this with different boundaries and try try bigger ranges and see
다른 경계를 두고 실험해 볼 수도 있어요 더 큰 범위를 시도해 보고 어떻게 되는지
how it goes.
보죠
But I found this to be easiest to work with and give good, good results across the board.
하지만 이렇게 하면 작업하기 쉽고 전반적으로 좋은 결과를 낼 수 있어요
So that's what is going on here.
그런 일이 벌어지고 있어요
Um, so let me save this and go back to our day.
이걸 저장하고 일상으로 돌아가 보죠
And I'm going to reload this because I made that little bug fix, restart kernel and run this again.
이걸 다시 로드하겠습니다 저 버그를 고치고 커널을 재시작하고 이걸 다시 실행했으니까요
Run our imports, log into Huggingface again.
수입 기록 조회하고 포옹 사이트에 다시 로그인해요
And now we're going to load in the appliances data set like we did before, and it's now going to be
이제 아까 했던 것처럼 데이터 어플라이언스를 로드할게요 제 컴퓨터를
hammering my computer.
박살 낼 거예요
I can see it doing its thing, and I'll tell you that before it took about a minute to load in all of
작업하는 게 보여요 1분 전에 데이터 세트 전체 어플라이언스를 로드했는데
the appliances data set last time, and this time it takes 0.2 minutes.
이번엔 0분 걸렸어요 2분
So it's rather faster when you have it broken into.
그래서 길들이는 게 더 빠르죠
Eight workers hammering my computer.
직원 8명이 내 컴퓨터를 망가뜨려요
And so I recommend you do the same.
여러분도 그렇게 하세요
But obviously pass in here workers equals four or less if you if you have fewer processes.
하지만 여기서 통과하면 작업자는 for less죠 프로세스가 적다면요
Um so that is the appliance data set.
그게 가전제품 데이터 세트예요
It has the 28,625 data points that are priced within that range that we have restricted it to.
제한된 범위 내에 가격 책정된 28,625개의 데이터 포인트가 있어요
Um, and they have all been loaded in, uh, let's have a look at the first one.
전부 차에 실었어요 첫 번째 사진을 보죠
Do you remember what the first one was?
첫 번째가 뭐였는지 기억하세요?
I did that again.
또 그랬네요
I did that last time.
저번에도 그랬잖아요
There we go.
됐어요
Try this.
이거 먹어 봐요
And here we go.
자, 보세요
It is the rack, roller and stud assembly kit.
랙, 롤러 스터드 조립 키트예요
Let's, uh, print its prompt.
프롬프트를 프린트하죠
And we'll hopefully also again convince ourselves that those, uh, clunky part numbers are filtered
또 스스로 납득할 수 있길 바라요 그 투박한 부품 번호는 걸러졌다고요
Yes they are.
맞아요
And this is, again, the dishwasher top wrack reels and stud assembly kit.
이건 식기세척기 톱 슬랙 릴과 스터드 조립 세트예요
And this is the door pivot block.
이건 문 피벗 블록이에요
Always needed one of those.
늘 그런 게 필요했죠
Uh, so there we go.
자, 됐어요
Uh, here are our data points loaded in for us.
로드된 데이터 포인트예요
Um, now it's going to be time for us to scale up and embark upon a much bigger problem.
이제 규모를 키워서 더 큰 문제에 착수할 때예요
We are going to be bringing in all of these data sets from the the Amazon.
아마존에서 모든 데이터를 가져올 거예요
Uh, Product Prices dataset repository.
제품 가격 데이터셋 저장소예요
I've selected these to be fairly similar kinds of things that are sort of stuff you might find at a
대형 가정용품 가게에서 볼 수 있는 물건들과 꽤 비슷한
large home retail store.
걸 골랐어요
So it's really almost anything on Amazon, not including stuff like clothes, beauty products, books
아마존에서 거의 모든 걸 취급해요 옷, 화장품, 책, 소프트웨어 그런
and software and things like that.
건 제외하고요
So it's everything that felt like it was sort of similar kind of stuff.
모든 게 비슷하게 느껴졌어요
Um, that would make a really good comprehensive data set.
포괄적인 데이터 집합이 될 거예요
So here are the data sets.
여기 데이터 집합이 있어요
And of course, um, if you're doing this as you follow along, if you're doing this when you do this,
물론 여러분이 따라 할 때 이걸 하고 이걸 할 때 이걸 한다면
as you do this, you can play with this and you can choose a different set of data.
이걸 갖고 놀면서 다른 데이터 세트를 선택할 수 있어요
If you wish.
원하신다면요
You could do this for clothes and see how it performs.
이렇게 옷을 만들고 어떻게 작동하는지 보세요
Um, if you are concerned about the size of data and you want to be doing things quicker, you can just
데이터의 크기가 걱정되고 작업을 빨리하고 싶다면 제한하면
limit it.
돼요
The appliances data set is one of the smallest ones there.
어플라이언스 데이터셋은 가장 작은 것 중 하나예요
Um, electronics is a nice and one in the middle.
전자 제품은 가운데에 있어요
So you could just focus on electronics.
전자 제품에만 집중할 수 있게요
Um, and you'll still have great fun, and you'll still get much the same kinds of performance results
음, 그래도 여전히 재미있고 성능도 데이터셋에서 얻을 수 있는 것과
as we will get with the entire data set.
동일한 결과를 얻게 될 거예요.
So those are all of the data set names.
이게 모든 데이터 세트 이름이에요
And now I'm going to read all of them in using the item loader to get after them.
이제 아이템 로더를 이용해 get을 불러오는 모든 것을 읽어볼게요.
And it's going to read them in one at a time.
한 번에 하나씩 읽어요
The biggest one is automotive which is the first one on the list.
가장 큰 도전은 자동차인데 목록 1번이에요
I've generally ordered it, I think with the biggest ones at the beginning.
전 보통 제일 큰 걸 주문해요
Um, it might take a bit longer for you because the first time you run this, it has to download the
시간이 좀 걸릴 거예요 처음 실행할 때 허깅페이스 데이터를 컴퓨터에
data from Huggingface to your computer because I've already run it once that step has happened, and
다운로드 해야 하거든요 그 단계를 거치고 나면 이미 실행했기 때문에 제 컴퓨터 캐시에서
so it just reuses it from a cache on my computer.
데이터를 재사용하는 거죠
Um, but it may it may take a bit, um, a bit longer for you because of that.
하지만 비트 때문에 시간이 좀 더 걸릴 거예요
And then off it will go.
그리고 떨어질 거예요
Now the total time for for on my computer is about 20 minutes.
제 컴퓨터로 작업하는 데 걸리는 시간은 20분 정도예요
Uh, my can see my, my CPU is flat out, so I'm going to take a pause and see you again right after
제 CPU가 완전히 다운된 걸 알 수 있죠 잠시 쉬었다가 다시 만나겠습니다 데이터가 모두 로드된
the break when the data has all loaded.
휴식 시간 직후에요